<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog by grhkm21</title>
    <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blog by grhkm21</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:13:15 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://grhkm21.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jacobi Quartics</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/jacobi-quartics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:13:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/jacobi-quartics/</guid>
      <description>This is a short note on Jacobi quartics and its relationship with elliptic curves.
Definition An elliptic curve in Jacobi quartic form is a curve of the form $J_a: y^2 = x^4 + 2ax^2 + 1$, where $\det(J)$, which is some multiple of $a^2 - 1$ here, is nonzero. This model of elliptic curves is important as it provides quicker point arithmetic. We shall prove that the curve $J_a$ is birationally equivalent to $E_a: 2v^2 = u^3 - 2au^2 + (a^2 - 1)u$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular Forms</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/modular-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/modular-forms/</guid>
      <description>I have decided to take on the topic of Modular Forms. I don&amp;rsquo;t intend to dive too in depth into the topic, since it is obviously a rich theory and has many prerequisites. However, I will try to get a basic understanding of what is it about and what the theory tries to answer.
References: Kilford (Book), Conrad (Notes), Conrad (Videos), Borcherds (Videos).
Update time:
Apr 24, 2023 (Modular forms, $q$-expansion, Eisenstein Series) Apr 29, 2023 (?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernoulli Polynomials</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/bernoulli-polynomials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 16:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/bernoulli-polynomials/</guid>
      <description>Please note that $p$ does not denote a prime, but instead usually an integer $p \geq 0$.
Existing lemmas Definition by recurrence:
$$ B_n = 1 - \sum_{k = 0}^{n - 1} \binom{n}{k} \frac{B_k}{n + 1 - k} $$
$$ B_n(x) = \sum_{k = 0}^n \binom{n}{k} B_{n - k}x^k $$
Faulhaber&amp;rsquo;s theorem:
$$ \sum_{k = 0}^{n - 1} k^p = \sum_{i = 0}^p B_i \binom{p + 1}{i} \frac{n^{p + 1 - i}}{p + 1} $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finite Realm of Random (498 points, 4 solves)</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/idek-finite-realm-of-random/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 12:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/idek-finite-realm-of-random/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Our team Black Bauhinia participated in the idekCTF 2023 which spans two days. Finite Realm of Random was an interesting math / crypto puzzle. In the end, only 3 teams solved it the intended way, and we were the second.
Problem Statement Description: I took a flag, and shuffled it. I took a part, and randomized it. I took the bits and pieces, and scattered them across the field. Now, only an haphazard mess remains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Pythagorean Triplets (1)</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/pythagorean-triplets-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 23:29:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/pythagorean-triplets-1/</guid>
      <description>Notes of Pythagorean Triplets This is a short article re-deriving the Tree of (primitive) Pythagorean Triplets, as well as a few interesting generalisations.
Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s begin with the equation $x^2 + y^2 = z^2$. A triplet $(x, y, z)$ satisfying the equation is called a Pythagorean Triplet, abbreviated PT. If we further have that $\gcd(x, y, z) = 1$, then we say that $(x, y, z)$ is a primitive PT, abbreviated PPT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonlinear Regression (1)</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/nonlinear-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 23:29:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/nonlinear-regression/</guid>
      <description>Notes on Non-Linear Regression 1. Linear Regression To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s recall how linear regression is done. We are given $n$ data points $(x_1, y_1), (x_2, y_2), \ldots, (x_n, y_n)$, and we are to make a linear model
$$ f(x) = ax + b $$
Such that the model &amp;ldquo;closely approximates&amp;rdquo; the data points, that is, to have $y_i \sim f(x_i)$. The residual is defined as the absolute difference between the interpolated data and the actual data:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Without Errors (396 pts, 6 solves, upsolve)</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/dice-learning-without-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 16:15:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/dice-learning-without-errors/</guid>
      <description>(Up-)Solved by: grhkm
Source of the problem: Dice CTF 2022
Self-Reflection I am actually very frustrated and annoyed at myself for this problem. During the CTF I was scared off by my lack of experience with this encryption scheme, and also just didn&amp;rsquo;t believe I can solve this challenge. As a result, I spent a lot of my time watching YouTube instead.
Approaching the end of the CTF, for absolutely no reason I decided I will try to take a look at the challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algebra (831 pts, 14 solves)</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/tet-algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 22:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/tet-algebra/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Our team Black Bauhinia participated in the TetCTF 2022 which spans two days. Algebra is the hardest Crypto challenge in the CTF. Mystiz and I (grhkm) together spent around 7 hours on this challenge.
Problem Statement Description: I threw some arbitrary operator into a finite field and, interestingly, I got a group!
Service: nc 139.162.61.222 13374
Binary: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1_fe-o44NH3pjHVLS_Bk965BPHO6QnVvO/view?usp=sharing
Solution Outline $x_3 = f(x_1, x_2)$ satisfies $\frac{1}{x_3} = [x^0]\left[\big(x + \frac{1}{x_1}\big)\big(x + \frac{1}{x_2}\big)\text{.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shares V1 (216 pts, 29 solves) / V2 (804 pts, 15 solves)</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/tet-shares/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/tet-shares/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Our team Black Bauhinia participated in the TetCTF 2022 which spans two days. Shares is an interesting two-part challenge. Mystiz and I (grhkm) spent around 10 hours in total on this challenge, $4$ on the first part and $6$ on the second.
Problem Statements Description: Yet another secret sharing scheme.
Service: nc 139.162.61.222 13371
Binary: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1sP0zKSKoF6TJZ-gtaUf7rv4dQ-bGr-cp/view?usp=sharing
Description: A new feature is added. Check it out!
Service: nc 139.162.61.222 13372</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pppp (117 pts, 70 solves)</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/seccon-pppp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 05:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/seccon-pppp/</guid>
      <description>Solved by: grhkm and TWY
Source of the problem: SECCON CTF 2021
Problem Statement Great research on witch has made it possible to split and duplicate messages.
problem.sage 8df65d6861d69ed6d461c5cd70b7157040534a0c
output.txt 2cf4e086b11751dfe9eaf758d26f8f0a765458d2
Solution Outline We found a (partial) general formula for exponent of an upper triangular matrix and solved the equations by comparing the entries.
Initial Observations We are given a matrix version of RSA. Essentially, we were asked to solve the matrix equation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hardest Path (300 pts, 9 solves)</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/hkcert-the-hardest-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 06:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/hkcert-the-hardest-path/</guid>
      <description>Source of the problem: HKCERT CTF 2021.
Summary of Problem Statement 寧願不揀最易的路 行極還未到
寧願你最後未傾慕 但信念安好
在意的 不再是 愛的煩惱
是哪樣做人 更清高
餘生那段旅途
與哪類人共舞
When you think reverse engineering is hard, try working on reverse engineering challenges &amp;gt; those need your algorithmic thinking skills!
nc chalp.hkcert21.pwnable.hk 28117
Attachments
the-hardest-path_e00c6aa7b64b8dc2a06e577937b5b07c.zip Solution Outline We have to find a path (represented by NEWS - North, East, West, South) from source _328518a497015157 to _8b0eb6f195ae182a, which is done by constructing call relationship graph and performing shortest path algorithm (such as Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unobserved Box (250 pts, 6 solves)</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/hkcert-unobserved-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 23:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/hkcert-unobserved-box/</guid>
      <description>Team Name: O0027 - UND3r 20 D53 H473r5 4ND r374K3r
Solved by: grhkm and Kaiziron
Source of the problem: HKCERT CTF 2021
Problem Statement All codes are uncertain before the measurement, and you will never make it.
Observe the code to get the flag.
nc chalp.hkcert21.pwnable.hk 28132
Solution Outline We dump the binary from 0x400000 to 0x405000 using format string and %8$s, then reverse engineer the check function for the flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 10:16:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I am Gareth, aka grhkm online. Hongkonger 🇭🇰 and currently studying maths at University of Warwick 🇬🇧. Interested in maths, cryptography (abbr. crypto), rhythm games, philosophy, indie and rock music. Currently looking for internship positions and research opportunities. Please contact me if you have any opportunities! I can provide my CV upon request.
This blog mainly contains writeups for interesting CTF and other algorithmic problems, but I plan to write some random blogs as well (someone suggested a song recommendation blog).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
