<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>math on Blog by grhkm21</title>
    <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/tags/math/</link>
    <description>Recent content in math on Blog by grhkm21</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 05:43:47 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://grhkm21.github.io/tags/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MA259 Notes</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/ma259-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 05:43:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/ma259-notes/</guid>
      <description>These are some summarised notes for MA259. I tried my best :)
Just like any other module, this module can be split into theoretical and computational. Obviously the theoretical parts are important as well, but in my opinion having a computational intuition helps see the big picture easier. Here, I only summarise the computational part of the module. For the proofs, you will need to look at the lecture notes themselves, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think they will be terribly important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jacobi Quartics</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/jacobi-quartics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:13:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/jacobi-quartics/</guid>
      <description>This is a short note on Jacobi quartics and its relationship with elliptic curves.
Definition An elliptic curve in Jacobi quartic form is a curve of the form $J_a: y^2 = x^4 + 2ax^2 + 1$, where $\det(J)$, which is some multiple of $a^2 - 1$ here, is nonzero. This model of elliptic curves is important as it provides quicker point arithmetic. We shall prove that the curve $J_a$ is birationally equivalent to $E_a: 2v^2 = u^3 - 2au^2 + (a^2 - 1)u$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular Forms</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/modular-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/modular-forms/</guid>
      <description>I have decided to take on the topic of Modular Forms. I don&amp;rsquo;t intend to dive too in depth into the topic, since it is obviously a rich theory and has many prerequisites. However, I will try to get a basic understanding of what is it about and what the theory tries to answer.
References: Kilford (Book), Conrad (Notes), Conrad (Videos), Borcherds (Videos).
Update time:
Apr 24, 2023 (Modular forms, $q$-expansion, Eisenstein Series) Apr 29, 2023 (?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernoulli Polynomials</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/bernoulli-polynomials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 16:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/bernoulli-polynomials/</guid>
      <description>Please note that $p$ does not denote a prime, but instead usually an integer $p \geq 0$.
Existing lemmas Definition by recurrence:
$$ B_n = 1 - \sum_{k = 0}^{n - 1} \binom{n}{k} \frac{B_k}{n + 1 - k} $$
$$ B_n(x) = \sum_{k = 0}^n \binom{n}{k} B_{n - k}x^k $$
Faulhaber&amp;rsquo;s theorem:
$$ \sum_{k = 0}^{n - 1} k^p = \sum_{i = 0}^p B_i \binom{p + 1}{i} \frac{n^{p + 1 - i}}{p + 1} $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finite Realm of Random (498 points, 4 solves)</title>
      <link>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/idek-finite-realm-of-random/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 12:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grhkm21.github.io/posts/idek-finite-realm-of-random/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Our team Black Bauhinia participated in the idekCTF 2023 which spans two days. Finite Realm of Random was an interesting math / crypto puzzle. In the end, only 3 teams solved it the intended way, and we were the second.
Problem Statement Description: I took a flag, and shuffled it. I took a part, and randomized it. I took the bits and pieces, and scattered them across the field. Now, only an haphazard mess remains.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
